Jaclyn Barcal

(847) 323-0667 jaclynbarcal@gmail.com

Objective

I am a physical therapist assistant (PTA) looking for consistent, full-time work in Austin, TX and surrounding areas. After 12 years of clinical experience, I am focusing on furthering my leadership skills. I am looking to find a position that challenges me, and ideally allows room for growth in the company. I am interested in joining a strong, coherent team of professionals who recognize and foster my potential.

Education

Grand Canyon University, Phoenix, AZ Bachelor's of Science in Psychology 2020-2022

Oakton Community College, Des Plaines, IL Associate of Applied Science 2008-2010

Experience

Lead PTA / Austin Injury Medical January 2018 – March 2023

Outpatient setting treating patients of all ages
Assisted in development of TBI treatment division
Communicated closely with interdisciplinary team (in-house pain management MD, chiropractor, lawyer and care coordinator) in order to provide the best patient care and treatment plan

PTA/ Texas Allied Therapy (Home Health)
December 2015- January 2020

Independent contractor servicing an 85-mile radius
Created/provided unique, engaging, and effective treatment sessions
Provided extensive family/caregiver education on fall prevention, transfer techniques, home safety modifications, and training on home exercise program